

615-310-7665

DevonCoxDev@gmail.com
 LinkedIn
 Portfolio Website
 GitHub

### **ABOUT**

I am a motivated creative with 6 months of experience in front-end software development and UI/UX design. Prior to becoming a developer, I was a professional musician. I am personable and an enthusiastic collaborator, fueled by a passion for creating honest, inclusive, and meaningful experiences for people. I embrace experimentation and have a growth mindset.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript ES6 | HTML5 | CSS3 | Sass | React JS | JSON | REST API | Firebase | Git GitHub | Agile | Scrum | User Research | UX Design | UI Design | Usability Testing Prototyping | Wireframing | Site Mapping | Personas | Figma | Adobe CC

### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | AUG 2020 - FEB 2021

Studied front-end web development and UI/UX design in a hands-on, learn-by-doing environment.

- Developed dynamic single-page applications using React in addition to modern ES6+ JavaScript
- Learned frontend fundamentals such as HTML5, CSS6, Sass, JSON, modular code, reusable components, and database structure using ERDs and Firebase
- Gained competency in UI/UX design fundamentals such as wire framing, prototyping research, user testing, journey mapping, site mapping, and personas
- Exposed to an Agile environment through frequent group projects including daily stand ups, planning, ticket assignments, and problem solving

#### **PROJECTS**

# Tidy Family View Code

Front-end capstone for Nashville Software School. Used LucidChart to create ERD. Used Figma to wireframe and mockup. Learned how to research and solve coding challenges, including JS and React, in an Agile environment with time constraints.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | JSON | React JS | Git | Github | Personas

## C43 Class Website View Site

Collaborated with team to build the class website. Led remote user tests. Used user feedback to find solutions and resolve design conflicts within the team. Built in React JS framework. Participated in creating and assigning tickets via Github.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | JSON | React JS | Git | Github | User Testing



615-310-7665

DevonCoxDev@gmail.com
 LinkedIn
 Portfolio Website
 GitHub

# TN.Gov Redesign View Case Study

Team project. Conducted multiple remote user tests to inform design decisions. Conducted research and analysis. Collaborated with team members to create a prototype and present our design.

Wireframing | Journey Mapping | User Testing | Prototyping

### **ZERO** View Code

UI/UX capstone for Nashville Software School. React application to help Nashvillians reduce trash. Built an API and learned how to make fetch calls using Firebase methods. Used JS promise.all to return an array of promises and solved a complex join table challenge.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Sass | React JS Git | Github | User Testing | Firebase

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEVON HEATH MUSIC Musician | Nov 2001 - Mar 2020

Worked solo and with other musicians and music professionals to record and tour. Collaborated with songwriters, producers, engineers, and musicians.

- · Produced and engineered records and demos using Protools, Logic, and other software
- · Designed album covers, websites, and march using Adobe CC
- Collaborated with many teams under time constraints to deliver finished product

MUSIC CITY ROLLIN' JAMBOREE MUSICIAN | JUL 2013 – MAR 2020

Part of a team that performed a 90 minute music and comedy show twice a day.

- Helped take them from a startup to one of the top 5 attractions in Nashville
- After 3 nominations, won the Music City Hitmaker Award from the city of Nashville for outstanding customer service
- Worked in a high pressure, fast paced environment in front of a live audience

#### **EDUCATION**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Front-end designer/developer - certificate

Full-time, 6 month web development bootcamp. Studied front-end web development and UI/UX design. Gained experience collaborating remotely in an Agile environment. Learned how to think like a developer and maintain a growth mindset.